Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder
of Family First Financial Services, MBA Finance, I have been working in the corporate sector for 15 years and
today I am presenting to you that on 20 June 2025, ICICI Prudential Life
Insurance has updated their term plan, I
have updated I Protect Smart and launched it as I Protect Smart Plus. Here you
will get some additional features which were not there in I Protect Smart. What are those features,
I will explain them in full detail in this video. If you like the video, then
definitely like, share and subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS
and if you like this plan and want to purchase the plan, then I
will give you the link in the description, by clicking there you
will be able to purchase this policy in online mode as well. If you want to purchase other products of ICICI Prudential Life Insurance,
whether it is a term policy, guaranteed plan, bonus plan, first
year income plan or pension plan, videos of all plans are on my
YouTube channel. It is available on Anil Raj Triple FS channel, you
can see the videos of those plans there. If you
want to understand in detail all the benefits and features of ICICI's I Protect Smart plan which is an old version, then
its complete video is available on my YouTube channel. You can see the picture on the side and if
you want to understand the rest of the old features, you can understand by going and watching this video on my channel.
Now what were the benefits in I Protect Smart?
There was life insurance cover. You got the benefit of inbuilt terminal illness. You
were getting the benefits of life stage. You were getting discount fee. If you
are a rider or a female, you were getting discount. If you want to take death benefit in lump sum, you want to take it
as income or you want to take some money in lump sum income,
as a rider you have accidental cover and you
were getting the benefit of critical illness. So all these benefits as it is will be available to you in this policy as well, but along with this, there
are some benefits which have come as plus, you will also get them. Let's understand. Plus
all the benefits that have been added now are one by one. The first plus point that they have launched is
the health protect rider. Earlier also they had
the benefit of 34 critical illnesses but this time they have given two options in the rider, whether you
want to take cover for 20 critical illnesses or you want to take cover for 60 illnesses. Secondly
, they have updated it that you
can add cover for critical illness up to Rs. 1.5 crore. The third update that they have done is that the earlier critical illness
in IPS was accelerated critical illness. For example, you
took a normal insurance cover of Rs. 1 crore and took the benefit of Rs. 20 lakh. Now
suppose you got diagnosed with any one or two critical illnesses out of the 34 and you
got Rs. 20 lakh. Now in future when death occurs, then by subtracting Rs. 1 crore minus Rs. 20 lakh, you would get Rs. 80 lakh.
You get a claim but the critical illnesses that you have now are above the base premium, i.e. if
you take an insurance cover of Rs. 1 crore or a critical illness of
Rs. 20 lakh, now if a critical illness is diagnosed, you will get Rs. 20 lakh and the same
insurance cover of Rs. 1 crore will continue. If there is death in the future, you will get that Rs. 1 crore separately.
The base cover that you had taken, you can choose either 20 critical illnesses instead of 34
or 60 critical illnesses, you can select any of the two options.
Along with this, there is a 20-year guarantee that your premium will not increase. If you
purchase a policy in health insurance where critical illness is also covered, there
your premium is revised according to age after a gap of every four years,
but here, suppose you purchase this policy in 2025, then your premium
will remain the same till 245, it will not change, it will not increase with age, this health protect rider
Any person from 18 to 55 years can purchase it, in which you
can pay limited premium and if you
want to take the policy term for 5 years, you can do so and if you want to take it for maximum 20 years, you can do so.
The second feature they have added is
Insta Payment on Claim Intimation, that is, if you
have taken an insurance cover of more than Rs. 1 crore and it has been more than 3 years since you took the policy and a claim comes,
then as soon as you submit the claim documents,
you will get Insta Pay Out of up to ₹ 1 lakh within one working day of the registration of the claim
, the remaining pay out will be given to the family or the nominee after the claim is completed.
But if for any reason the claim gets rejected, then the ₹3 lakhs
given by the company to you may have to be refunded to you. The third plus that they have added
is premium break i.e. cover continuation benefit. If
5 years of the policy you have taken are completed, then in every 5 year gap, except the last 3 years,
if you want to take this premium break, then you can take it. For this, you
will have to tell the company 30 days in advance that I do not want to pay this premium this year or I will not
be able to pay it, even then the policy will continue for you, during that time if a claim comes, even then
the company will provide the entire claim to you, so this is an excellent feature which is
known as premium break or cover continuation benefit. For example, there is a person
who is paying a premium of ₹16,000, is 35 years old and he
is purchasing this policy and let us assume that he does not pay the premium in the sixth year, then
in the seventh year when that premium If he goes to pay the premium then he can continue the policy by paying
₹16,000 + ₹16,000 or ₹32,000 premium. In this way, if he
wants to take a break in the future also, after 5 years, if he wants to take a break in the 12th year,
he can take it, if he wants to take a break in the 17th year, he can take it, but
in the last 3 years of the policy, he cannot take this option of premium break.
They have added another great feature that suppose when you purchase the policy, let's assume that your age
is 35 years and you have selected the policy for regular premium payment term and your coverage
is till the age of 70, then it means that you have taken a policy term of 35 years, but the policy
has completed 3 years. Now you think that no, who will pay the premium for these 35 years? You
want me to convert this policy into limited pay, that is, I
should pay the premium for 5 years, my policy will continue or I will be covered for 10 years only. I make premium
payment but my insurance cover should continue for 35 years. Let's assume that
you have a good income, your business is running well and you
are capable of paying a large amount of premium at one go and if you don't want to pay premium every year, then
you can complete your regular premium payment term in limited premium payment term as well.
After 3 years, the company has launched another great feature here
, the Life Stage Benefit. This benefit was available earlier as well but with some limit
because you can take 50%. You
can add a maximum cover of up to Rs. 50 lakhs only. But this time they have removed that limit from here. Now suppose for
example, when you purchased the policy, you were unmarried and after a few years you
got married and now you want to increase the insurance cover. Suppose at that time your
insurance cover was Rs. 2 crore and now you want to increase the insurance cover by 50% on marriage, then you
can increase it by Rs. 1 crore as well. Similarly, 25% on the birth of first child is added
for second child. 25% at birth If you purchase a home, you
want to increase the insurance cover up to 100% of the home loan, you can do so, but there is a term and condition that this option
is available only on regular premium payment policies and
not in limited pay. Also, in the year in which you add this benefit and
take extra insurance cover, at that time, you will have to pay the premium that comes as per your AS as per the underwriting guidelines.
So, there is another plus in the plus that
here you are getting a discount, earlier if you
were taking a cover of 1 crore or more and you were a salaried person, you were getting a discount, but this time you
are getting discount even on a cover of 50 lakhs. Secondly, earlier you
were getting a discount of up to 10% if you were taking the policy in regular pay and you were salaried. Now it has
become 12.5% ​​and in limited pay you will still get a discount of 15%. If you are salaried,
you will get a discount of up to 15% of your salary. 5% if you purchase the policy online. So you will get 5%
discount online and if you are a female then you will get an additional 15%
discount As for the eligibility criteria, this policy can be purchased by a person
from 18 to 60 years of age. Here you can pay the premium in annual mode
, you can purchase it in semi-annual mode, you can purchase it in monthly mode
but you cannot purchase this policy in quarterly mode. Here the premium
payment term is that you can pay single premium,
you can take the option of 5 pay, 7 pay, 10 pay, 15 pay and pay till Rs.860. You can also take the policy term for a minimum of 5 years, maximum
99 minus your entry age. You can also select a policy term of that many years.
The minimum sum asset in this will be Rs. 50 lakh, there is no maximum limit in this and
as a rider, you can add accidental death benefit rider and
You can also add a rider for critical illness benefit.
They have upgraded the financial eligibility a lot. Earlier,
if a person aged between 18 and 30 years used to take a term policy, he
would get an insurance cover of 25 times his income, now he will get 35 times the income. That means, suppose you are 30 years old and your
income is ₹1 lakh, then earlier you could take an insurance cover of only up to ₹5 crore, now you
will be able to take an insurance cover of up to 3.5 crore. Now let us understand the benefit illustration of the new product ICICI I Protect
Smart Plus. Let us assume a 35
-year-old person named Anil Rajpurohit is purchasing the policy.
He will pay the premium for 15 years. The policy will run for 35 years. Here, he
is taking a natural life cover of ₹1 crore, accidental cover of ₹1 crore and
critical illness cover of ₹1 lakh. For 60 critical illnesses, the critical illness
will run for 20 years. Here,
for the natural cover of 1 crore, the premium will be ₹27,315. For the accidental cover of 1 crore, the
premium will be ₹11,585 for a year. But you are
getting this benefit for the entire 35 years. You are getting critical illness for ₹774. Here,
after GST, you will have to pay ₹5576. I have considered the customer as a salary here, so you
will get a discount of 15%. From the first year onwards, the premium will be ₹763
.
Now, how much GST is applicable here? Suppose
you had to take only pure cover, then it would have been available for ₹27,315. Including GST, you would have to pay ₹
32,000 in the first year and then ₹37,000 from the next year. If you want to add riders, then you
can add riders in this policy as per your requirement. And if you want to add riders for criticality, then you can add riders in this policy as per
your requirement. If you take 20 instead of 60
, then your premium gets reduced a bit, so you
can take it accordingly. Here you will also get to see surrender benefit. The big amount is not visible here, but there is a special exit feature, which you
get the benefit after 25 years or if you turn 60 whichever is earlier. If you see here,
the surrender benefit is visible only ₹46,000, but in special exit benefit,
the basic premium that you have paid of ₹27,300, ₹15 without rider,
the total premium paid without GST, you can take back at the age of
60 or 25 years policy term whichever is earlier.
Let us understand with another example, suppose there is an HAI customer, his age
is also 35 years and he wants to take a bigger insurance cover. He will pay the premium for 15 years, he
is taking the policy for 35 years, but this time the premium that he has paid is for 15 years.
If you are taking insurance cover, life cover, you are taking it for ₹1 crore
, accidental cover of ₹ crore and critical illness benefit of ₹1.5 crore,
that too for 60 critical illnesses. If any one of these critical illnesses is diagnosed,
you will get full ₹1.5 crore. For this , it does not matter whether your hospital bill is 10 lakhs
or 50 lakhs, you will get full ₹1.5 crore. For this, if you already have a health insurance policy, you
can claim there too.
It is not that if you get a claim here, you will not get it there. Plus
, you have to pay premium for 15 years. Critical illness will run for you for 20 years and the rest of the
accidental death benefit rider and natural cover will run for you for 35 years.
Now your premium for natural cover will come.
You will get accidental cover of 1.96 lakh for 15 years. You will get it for ₹34,756 and you will get critical illness for ₹16,000.
In front of this ₹16,000, if you get any of the 60 critical illnesses, you
will get ₹1.5 crores at once and your natural cover and accidental cover will continue.
Later, if there is death in the future, then you will get a full ₹1 crore as death benefit
and if there is death in an accident, then you will get 10 + 3 crores of that too. So
in the first year, you will get a discount of 15% if you are salaried, if you are female, then
there is an additional 15% discount and if you purchase online, then
you will also get an additional 5% discount. So the premium is ₹10497. From next year, you
will have to pay a premium of around ₹4.5 lakh. You can see all the other benefits here. If
you buy the policy when you reach the age of 60, then you can avail the special If you want to take exit benefit,
you can take it. There is no loan facility available in this policy.
Tax benefit will be available in section ATC of income tax. Death benefit
is always tax free. Talking about grace period and
free look period in section 1010D of income tax, you
will get revival period for 5 years. Surrender benefit is not available in regular pay. Surrender in limited pay
You can get the benefit If I summarize this video, if I summarize this plan, then it
is an excellent plan, the brand is also very good, the claim settlement ratio
is also 99.30%, the premium is also quite affordable, there are many options for premium payment,
you can take the policy till the age of 99 years, salaried people are getting discounts,
you are getting discounts on buying online, females are getting extra discounts separately
and these different great new features
have been added keeping in mind your needs, you can take a critical illness rider up to ₹1.5 crore,
₹1.5 crore plus in this your premium does not increase for 20 years,
if I talk about critical illness, if you want to add accidental death benefit rider to it, you
can also do it, so if you want to purchase this policy, then I
have given a link in the description, you can purchase this policy by clicking on it,
if you liked the video, then before leaving, definitely like my YouTube channel Anil Rajput Trifle
FS Share and subscribe If you want to
understand other products of any other company or want to get information about some other product
or you want me
to make a video on a particular product or particular topic then you can write in the comment below
and I will try my best to make a video on that.
Thank you so much Jai Hind